A little about me, your instructor, my name is Nina Zackranko.
You might also know me as NNJ and Twitter.
I've written software for some pretty cool companies over the course of my decade-long career
and engineering.
I've worked at Meetup.
I've worked at HBO, writing software for satellite computers.
I worked at Reddit.
These days I work at Microsoft is a cloud developer advocate, focusing on Python.
I've been at professional Python developer for the past five or six years now
and it's absolutely my favorite language.
If you'd like to stay in touch with me after the course,
there's some links here on the course website.
This is an intermediate Python course.
You might also see it referred to as day two throughout the course website.
During this course, we're going to start getting more comfortable
with some of the more advanced aspects of Python,
like classes, list-comprehensions, and the standard library.
At the end of the day, you're going to know enough to build a small interactive
website using the Flask web framework.
Know that to fully participate in today's class,
you must have VS Code set up locally, along with a Python version greater than 3.7.
You must be familiar with all of the concepts from introduction to Python,
which you might see referred to as day one.
Clicking through to the intro to Python section.
You should be familiar with Python conventions, like Pepe,
basic data types, and variables, numbers, strings,
the common errors, and common mistakes you might make as a Python developer.
Functions defining them arguments, function scope.
The more advanced types of Python, the list, the tuple, the set, and the dictionary,
you must be familiar with mutability, and know that a tuple is a immutable data structure,
while list set and dictionary is mutable.
You should know about Boolean logic, the truthiness of a value in Python,
as well as how to make comparisons, such as greater than less than, and end or not,
those Boolean operators. You should know how to loop along with control statements.
You should know the if statement, else four loops, wall loops, and break,
continue, and return. Lastly, you should know how to work with Python programs,
how to run them, what the main method is, exceptions, and tracebacks, and how to
work with simple libraries. Lastly, you should know a little bit about what an API is,
and how to work with them, requests, and responses, HTTP status codes, and how to use the request
library and Python. If you're not sure if you know these topics, I would suggest that you go ahead
and watch the intro to Python course first. You're going to get a lot more value out of intermediate
Python if you have a solid understanding of these foundational concepts. If you're choosing
to join us for intermediate Python without doing the intro Python course first, go ahead and scroll
up to the top of the course website, click on the course introduction, and then go to the
requirements settings. You'll have to go through all of these steps to be able to follow along
with the exercises in intermediate Python.